

# Mintra Ruensuk PhD student at UNIST

Ulsan, South Korea



+82 010 40971979



mintra-ruensuk.github.io



mintra@unist.ac.kr

## About me —

Mintra is a second year PhD student in the Graduate School of Creative Design Engineering at Ulsan National Institute of Science and Technology (UNIST), South Korea. She is a member of Interactions Lab. Mintra's research focus includes affective computing, human-computer interaction and software engineering. Her current research aims to use mobile sensing and interactions to detect transient emotions during the social media use.

## Skills ——

Machine Learning Ruby on Rails Laravel D3 HTML5 CSS, Bootstrap **JavaScript** Swift, Andriod Selenium SOL CLI

#### Education

since 2017 Ph.D. in Design Engineering (Human-Computer Interaction)

School of Creative Design Engineering, UNIST, South Korea

Current research title: Exploiting Sensors to Detect Transitory Emotions During Social Media Use

2010-2012 M.Sc. in Computer Science (with specialization in Software Engineer-

ing)

School of Engineering and Technology Asian Institute of Technology, Thailand

Thesis: Voice, Gesture, and Web Interfaces for Human-Robot Inter-

action in Service Environments

2005-2009 B.Sc. in Information Technology (First Class Honour)

Faculty of Information Science and Technology Mahanakorn University of Technology, Thailand

Project: Information Technology Jobs Matching By Groovy on Grails

## **Employment**

2015-2017 Lecturer

Department of Information Technology Faculty of Business and Technology

Stamford International University, Thailand

2015-2015

Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Science Rajamangala University of Technology Thanyaburi, Thailand

Senior Software Engineer 2012-2015

Think Blue Data, Thailand

2009-2010 Lecturer

Faculty of Information Science and Technology Mahanakorn University of Technology, Thailand

### **Publications**

2019 Taewan Kim, Mintra Ruensuk, Hwajung Hong. In Helping a Vulnera-

ble Bot, You Help Yourself: Designing a Social Bot as a Care-Receiver to Promote Mental Health and Reduce Stigma. In Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

(CHI'20), to appear.

2019 Mintra Ruensuk, Hyunmi Oh, Eunyong Cheon, Hwajung Hong, Ian

Oakley. Detecting Negative Emotions during Social Media Use on Smartphones, in ACM Asian CHI Symposium: Emerging HCI Research

Collection, to appear.

2019 Mintra Ruensuk, Jayeong Yoon, Choeun Park. Amor: Supporting

> Emerging Adult Couples to Manage Finances for a Common Goal, in ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems

2019 Extended Abstracts (CHI'19 EA). [doi] [13% acceptance]

2019 Sanghyun Ma, Mintra Ruensuk, ChaJoong Kim. Design considerations

for promoting the mental health of young academics - a case of Korean graduate, in the 22nd International Conference on Engineering

Design (ICED19), to appear.

2018 Mintra Ruensuk. Detecting Emotions using Smartphone Sensors: Technique to Raise Self-Awareness for Social Media Users, in ACM In-

ternational Joint Conference and 2018 International Symposium on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing and Wearable Computers (Ubi-

comp'18), Broadening Participation Workshop [doi]

- 2017 Sirisilp Kongsilp, <u>Mintra Ruensuk</u>, Matthew N. Dailey, and Takashi Komuro. *Tablet Fish Tank Virtual Reality: a Usability Study*, in International Conference on Artificial Reality and Telexistence Eurographics Symposium on Virtual Environments (ICAT-EGVE'17) [doi]
- 2016 <u>Mintra Ruensuk</u>. An implementation to reduce internal/external interruptions in Agile software development using pomodoro technique, in 2016 IEEE/ACIS 15th International Conference on Computer and Information Science (ICIS) [doi]
- 2015 <u>Mintra Ruensuk</u>, Buraskorn Yoosuka and Pongpol Nilaphruek. *A Special Capstone Course for Exchange Students on Agile Software Development Using Scrum Methodology*, in PKRU Conference on Development of New and Innovation Research for the AEC
- 2010 <u>Mintra Ruensuk</u>, Woraphon Lilakiatsakun. *Information Technology Jobs Matching By Groovy on Grails*, in Proceedings of Conference on Electrical Engineering/Electronics Computer Telecommunications and Information Technology (ECTI-CARD'2010)

#### Awards & Honors

- 2019 Outstanding Poster Presentation Award SIGCHI Korea Local Chapter at Daejeon
- 2019 SIGCHI Student Travel Grant (SSTG)

Conference registration waiver and \$1,800 travel grant for attending CHI'19

2019 ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'19)

Student Design Competition (advance to the second round)

2018 ACM Grant for The 2018 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing (Ubicomp'18)

Conference registration waiver and \$600 travel grant for attending Ubicomp 2018

2017 - 2021 UNIST CDE Scholarship

4 years awarded for tuition and stipend for Ph.D. studies

2010 - 2012 Royal Thai Government Fellowship

2 year awarded for tuition for graduate studies

2005 - 2009 Mahanakorn University of Technology Scholarship

4 year awarded for tuition for undergraduate studies

### Volunteer experience

2019 ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI'19)

Student Volunteer

2018 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous

Computing (Ubicomp'18)

Student Volunteer